A Guide to the George Campbell Peery Papers, 1899-1945
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
George Campbell Peery Papers, 1899-1945
Library of Virginia
35134
7.1 cu. ft. (in part, photocopies); scrapbooks on microfilm (Misc. reels 2298-3308).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ben H. Linberry, Tazewell, Virginia, 31 October 1995.
Biographical/Historical Information
Born in Cedar Bluff, Tazewell County, Virginia on 28 October 1873. Graduate of Emory and Henry College (1894); Washington and Lee University law school (1897); member of U.S. House of Representatives (1923- 1929); governor of Virginia (1934-1938). Died in Richlands, Virginia on 14 October 1952. Buried in Maplewood Cemetery, Tazewell County, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Includes personal and general correspondence, 1899-1928, containing information mostly on Peery's law practice in Wise and Tazewell County, Virginia; speeches, 1913-1943 and undated, to civic organizations in Virginia, as well as some campaign addresses; campaign files, 1922-1925, which include correspondence; miscellaneous records, including West Point and Naval Academy appointments, 1924-1927, and information on Peery's residence in Wise, Virginia, dated 1908-1909; and scrapbooks.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Personal, 1899-1900 (Box 1, Folder 1-18)
  - Personal, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 19-31)
  - Personal, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 32-47)
  - Personal, 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 48-62)
  - Personal, 1906-1908 (A-L) (Box 1, Folder 63-70)
  - Personal, 1906-1908 (M-Z) (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Personal, 1908-1909 (Box 2, Folder 9-23)
  - Personal, 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 24-38)
  - Personal, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 39-53)
  - Personal, 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 54-69)
  - Personal, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 1-21)
  - General, 1923-1924 (A-S) (Box 3, Folder 22-44)
  - General, 1923-1924 (S-Z) (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Personal, 1925-1927 (Box 4, Folder 6-27)
  - Personal, 1926-1928 (Box 4, Folder 28-47)
  - General, 1926-1927 (H-Z) (Box 5, Folder 1-20)
  - Personal, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 21-44)
  - General, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 45-59)
- Speeches
  - Wise High School - May 22, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Saltville High School Commencement Exercises - 1924 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Game Refuge Bill (H.R. 745), U.S. Congress - February 20, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Marion Junior College Commencement Exercises, Marion - May 31, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Speech, Jonesville - September 13, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Martha Washington College Commencement Exercises - 1927 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Democratic State Convention, Roanoke - June 21, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Emory and Henry College 91st Annual Commencement - June 11, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - State Teachers College 20th Annual Commencement, Fredericksburg - June 8, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Norfolk Lodge No. 38, B.P.O.E. Memorial Service - December 6, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Democratic National Convention Seconding Speech, Chicago (Not Delivered) - 1932 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Trustees of Public Schools - November 22, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Suffolk Lodge No. 685, B.P.O.E. Memorial Service - December 4, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - American Legion, Richmond - April 19, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Amherst Court House - June 12, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Campaign Speech, Louisa - October 9, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Radio Address/State Elections - October 28, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Inaugural Address - January 17, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Joint Session of the General Assembly - February 7, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce - February 8, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Opening of Restored Capitol, Williamsburg - February 24, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cape Henry - April 26, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Essex County Schools, Tappahannock - May 10, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Presentation of Statues of Washington and Lee in Statuary Hall, U.S. Capitol - May 18, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Lafayette and Virginia" - May 20, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Emory and Henry College Commencement Exercises - June 5, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Collegiate School for Girls Graduation, Richmond - June 8, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Radio Address/Read Admiral Byrd - June 10, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - University of Virginia Commencement Exercises - June 12, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Roanoke Island, North Carolina - August 18, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Radio Address/Orange County - August 21, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Sesqui-centennial Celebration of Methodism in America, Richmond - September 23, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Radio Address/Orange County Bicentennial - September 25, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Fort Harrison Celebration - September 30, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Veterans' Hospital Dedication, Roanoke - October 19, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Mary Washington Chapter, No. 290, Order of Ahepa, Fredericksburg - October 21, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Annual Session of State Grange, Richmond - October 25, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Radio Address/Gadsby's Tavern - October 30, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Gadsby's Tavern - October 30, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Campaign Speech - November, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Opening of Virginia-West Virginia Highway, Harrisonburg - November 9, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - American Legion, Williamsburg - November 11, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Radio Address/Education - November 22, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Virginia Education Association - November 30, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Trial Justices Courts in Virginia, Richmond - January 25, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - President's Birthday - January 30, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Young Democratic Clubs of the 3rd Congressional District of Virginia - March 6, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - St. Paul's Church, 70th Anniversary of the Evacuation of Richmond - April 3, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Restoration of Civil War Relics by Mayor Phillips of Stamford, Connecticut, Richmond - April 3, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - WJSV Radio Address/Garden Week and Apple Blossom Festival - April 21, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Cape Henry - April 26, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Tau Kappa Alpha Convention, Lynchburg - April 27, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Synopsis of Calland's Address - April 27, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - 72nd Anniversary of the Battle of Chancellorsville - May 2, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Admiral Richard Byrd Welcome - May 10, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Medical College of Virginia Commencement Exercises, Richmond - May 28, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Radio Address/Rear Admiral Byrd - June 10, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Governor's Conference, Biloxi, Mississippi - June 13-15, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Convention of Young Democrats (Not Used) - September 13, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Dr. Hunter Holmes McGuire Bronze Memorial, Richmond - October 11, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Virginia Real Estate Association, Lynchburg - October 11, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Robert E. Lee Memorial Foundation, Stratford - October 12, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - American Legion, Richmond - November 10, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - General Fitzhugh Lee Memorial - November 19, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Richmond Light Infantry Blues - December 20, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Joint Session of Virginia General Assembly - January 8, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Williamsburg - January 18, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - WRVA Radio Address - January 26, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Radio Address/13th Annual Shenandoah Apple Blossom Festival - April 24, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Richmond College Social Science Society - April 24, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Cape Henry - April 26, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - 178th Anniversary of James Monroe's Birth, Fredericksburg - April 28, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Jamestown - May 13, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Alexandria - May 20, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Hollywood Cemetery, Richmond - May 30, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Virginia Tech Commencement Exercises - June 8, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - State Democratic Convention - June 16, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Dedication of American Legion Clubhouse, Hopewell - June 19, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Shenandoah National Park Dedication - July 3, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - 110th Anniversary of the Death of Thomas Jefferson, Monticello - July 4, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - WHIS Radio Dedication, Bluefield - July 26, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - 280th Division of the American Expeditionary Forces of World War I, Richmond - August 6, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - State Bar Association - August 7, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - School Dedication, Colonial Beach - October 2, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Ancient and Honorable Artillery Co. Banquet - October 6, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Campaign Speech, Manassas - October 10, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - City of Lynchburg Sesqui-centennial - October 14, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Campaign Speech, Hampton - October 16, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Surrender at Yorktown Commemoration - October 19, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Lila Meade Valentine Memorial, Richmond - October 20, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - John Bannister Tabb Memorial Plaque Dedication - November 7, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Medical College of Virginia 99th Anniversary - December 1, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - General Assembly - December 14, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Radio Address/Flood Disaster Relief - January 27, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - WRVA Radio Address/Shenandoah Apple Blossom Festival - April 16, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Dedication of Memorial Plinth at Manakintowne - April 18, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Introduction of Walter Lippman, College of William and Mary - April 23, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - 150th Anniversary of the Framing of the United States Constitution, Philadelphia - May 20, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Farmville State Teachers College Commencement Address - June 8, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Virginia and West Virginia Bankers' Associations Joint Conference, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia - June 24, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Fitzhugh Lee Camp No. 1, United Spanish War Veterans - August 12, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Unveiling of Tablet Commemorating Ratification of Constitution - September 17, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Baptist Church of Richmond (African-American) - October 10, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Radio Address/Muhlenberg and Harry Byrd - January 1, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Joint Session of Virginia General Assembly - January 12, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - William Peery Monument, Tazewell - July 4, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Tazewell Methodist Church - February 21, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Tax Bill (Box 6A, Folder 1)
  - Educational Address (Box 6A, Folder 2)
  - State Democratic Convention - Speech by Senator Harry F. Byrd (Box 6A, Folder 3)
  - Emory and Henry College Alumni Address (Box 6A, Folder 4)
  - The Old Bell House (Box 6A, Folder 5)
  - John Richard Saunders Memorial Service (Box 6A, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Alumni Association (Box 6A, Folder 7)
  - State Health Department (Box 6A, Folder 8)
  - State Planning (Box 6A, Folder 9)
  - WRVA Radio Address/National Reemployment Service (Box 6A, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Speeches (Box 6A, Folder 11-13)
  - Message of George C. Peery, Governor of Virginia, 1934-1938 (2 copies) (Box 6A, Folder 14)
- Campaign Files
  - Correspondence, 1922-1925 (A-C, H-J, N, W) (Box 6A, Folder 15-20)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1922 (Box 6A, Folder 21)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1922 (Box 6A, Folder 22)
  - Congratulatory telegrams, 1922 (Box 6A, Folder 23)
  - Congratulatory telegrams, 1922 (Box 6A, Folder 24)
  - Campaign photo (Box 6A, Folder 25)
  - List of Virginia Democratic Committee District Chairmen and County Managers for George C. Peery, Candidate for the Gubernatorial Nomination, 1933 (Box 6A, Folder 26)
- Miscellaneous Records
  - Nanola G. Peery - Insurance Policies - Winter Haven, Florida Property, 1928-1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Journal of the Constitutional Convention of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photos from George C. Peery scrapbook, volume VII (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Loose George C. Peery scrapbook material, all volumes (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - West Point and Naval Academy Appointments, 1924-1927 (Box 7, Folder 5-10)
  - George C. Peery Residence, Wise, Virginia - 1908-1909 (Box 8, Folder 1-13)
  - Card Indexes to Correspondence (Box 9-10)
- Scrapbooks
  - Vol. I: January - June 1934 (Box 2298)
  - Vol. II: June - November 1934 (Box 2299)
  - Vol. III: November 1934 - January 1935 (Box 2299)
  - Vol. III: January - February 1935 (Box 2300)
  - Vol. IV: February - June 1935 (Box 2300)
  - Vol. V: June - November 1935 (Box 2301)
  - Miscellaneous - 1932 - 1933 (Box 2301)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch and Richmond News Leader clippings, 1933 (Box 2302)
  - Vol. VI: November 1935 - April 1936 (Box 2302)
  - Vol. VII: April - August 1936 (Box 2303)
  - Vol. VIII: September 1936 - May 1937 (Box 2304)
  - Vol. IX: May 1937 - January 1938 (Box 2305)
  - Miscellaneous - 1925 - 1929 (Box 2305)
  - Virginia newspaper clippings, February - November 1933 (Box 2306)
  - Miscellaneous - 1922 - 1923, 1926 (Box 2306)
  - Virginia newspaper clippings, 1933 (Box 2307)
  - Letters from Father Byrd, 1933 (Box 2307)
  - Miscellaneous - 1937 (Box 2307)
  - Miscellaneous - 1937 (Box 2308)